littlepassports.com 2018-11-27

# Privacy Policy

**The privacy policy was last revised on October 31, 2018.**

Little Passports owns and provides various websites, services, materials and software available to the public at and through https://www.littlepassports.com and related URL’s (“the Site”, and collectively with the services, materials, and software, “the Services”). Little Passports respects your privacy and values your trust. In this Privacy Policy, we may refer to Little Passports as “Little Passports,” “us,” or “we.” We shall refer to users of the Site as “You” or “User.” This privacy policy will inform you of the following:

  * What kind of information is collected; 
  * Who collects the information; 
  * How the information is used; 
  * With whom the information may be shared; 
  * Where the information may be transferred, accessed, and stored; 
  * What choices are available to you regarding its collection, use, and distribution; 
  * The security procedures that are in place to protect the information; 
  * How long information may be kept; 
  * Children’s privacy; and 
  * How you can correct inaccuracies in the information.

BY USING THE SITE OR SERVICES, YOU ACCEPT THE TERMS SET FORTH IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND IN OUR USER AGREEMENT. This Privacy Policy is incorporated by reference into the User Agreement and any terms not defined in this Privacy Policy will have the meanings set forth in the User Agreement.

Little Passports reserves the right, at its sole discretion, to change, modify, update, add, or remove portions of this Privacy Policy at any time, with or without notice to you. Please check this Privacy Policy periodically for changes. Your continued use of the Site after the posting of any changes to the Privacy Policy will signify your acceptance of those changes.

### Information We Collect and How We Use Information

The types of information we may collect (directly from you or from third party sources) and our privacy practices depend on the nature of the relationship you have with us and the requirements of applicable law. Some of the ways that we may collect information include:

  * You may provide information directly to us when you interact with the Site, make a purchase, participate in surveys or sweepstakes, and request Services or information
  * As you navigate the Site, certain passive information may also be collected about your visit, including through cookies and similar technologies as described below.
  * We may combine information that you provide us through this Site with other information we have received from you, whether online or offline, or from other sources such as from our vendors, as further described in this Privacy Policy.

We endeavor to collect only that information which is relevant for the purposes of providing the Services. Below are the ways we collect information and how we use it.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information.** Non-personally identifiable information is information that, by itself, does not identify a specific individual. Examples of non-personally identifiable information include, but are not limited to, log files, web beacons, the type of internet browser you are using, the type of computer operating system you are using, the time and date of your use of the Site, age and gender, location (at a local or national level), and whether you clicked on hypertext links within the Site. We may collect non-personally identifiable information while you use the Site. Non-personally identifiable information also includes information that is stripped of all identifiers or that has been combined with other information such that no individual can be identified.

**Use of Non-Personally Identifiable Information.** We may create and/or use non-personally identifiable information for a number of reasons, including to generate user statistics that we may provide to prospective advertisers or partners, and that we may use to enhance your experience using the Site and generally improve the Site and Services. We may also use the non-personally identifiable information to generate statistics that we may provide to you and to other Users of the Site. We also may provide non-personally identifiable information to our affiliates, partners, and contractors so that they can perform services related to the Site for us. If we provide any non-personally identifiable information to anyone else, we will provide it in a manner that does not include any personally identifiable information about any individual users.

We and third parties that provide content, advertising, or other functionality on our Site or with our Services may use different types of technologies to collect non-personally identifiable information, including cookies, local storage, single-pixel GIFs, and other technologies (“Technologies”). We use Technologies that are essentially small data files placed on your computer, tablet, mobile phone, or other devices (referred to collectively as a " **device** ") that allow us to record certain pieces of information whenever you visit or interact with our Sites, Services, applications, messaging, and tools, and to recognize you across devices.

  * Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer’s hard drive to identify your computer to our servers. If your browser is configured to accept cookies, we will use cookies to recognize your computer when you visit the Site so that we can provide you with a better experience and improve the quality of the Site. If you wish, you can configure your browser to disable cookies. If you disable cookies, however, it may impair the functionality of the Site, and we encourage you not to disable cookies.
  * A pixel tag (also known as a web beacon) is a piece of code embedded on the Site that collects information about users’ engagement on that web page. The use of a pixel allows us to record, for example, that a user has visited a particular web page or clicked on a particular advertisement.

Our Site may include social media features such as the Facebook “Like” button and LinkedIn (that might include widgets such as the share this button or other interactive mini-programs). These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. These social media features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

We may also use Google Analytics and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting to collect information regarding visitor behavior and visitor demographics on some of our Services, and to develop Site content. This analytics data is not tied to any PII. For more information about Google Analytics, please visit [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/). You can opt out of Google’s collection and processing of data generated by your use of the Site by going to <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

If you would like to opt-out of the Technologies we employ on our Site, applications, or tools, you may do so by blocking, deleting, or disabling them as your browser or device permits.

**Use of Non-Personally Identifiable Information.** Little Passports may use non-personally identifiable information collected to improve the quality of Little Passports' Services; for example, by diagnosing service or technology problems, by assessing and maintaining security, by increasing ad placements on web sites that are generating more web traffic, by presenting you with information that we think you would be interested in seeing, or by allowing you to log in or access your profile information automatically. We may also use the information to count and recognize returning users.

We may use non-personally identifiable information collected to determine user demographics, interests, and behavior and may market Little Passports products by sharing non-personally identifiable information with potential customers or partners. Little Passports also may provide your non-personally identifiable information to contractors so that they can perform services for us. We may also utilize service providers to assist us in aggregating customer information. We may then share such aggregated non-personally identifiable information with prospective marketing partners, advertisers and others.

**Links to third parties may be displayed on the Site.** Links to third-party websites, including third-party advertisers, may be displayed on the Site. If you choose to click on a third-party link, we may provide non-personally identifiable information to the owning third-party. Also, any such third-party may use cookies or other technologies to collect information when you are visiting their web sites. The information third parties collect is governed by their individual privacy policies. Little Passports does not take responsibility nor can guarantee the content of such third-party privacy policies. In addition, Little Passports may use third-party advertising companies to display advertisements on the Site. These companies may leverage information about your activity on the Site in order to help them provide more relevant ads to you.

**Personally Identifiable Information (“PII”).** PII is any piece of information that can be traced back to a specific individual user and so might be used to uniquely identify, contact, or locate that specific individual. When you use various services or features on the Site, we may ask you to provide PII. For example, if you choose to register at the Site, you may be asked to provide your name, email address, password and/or username, and if you choose to use other services on the Site, you may be asked to provide additional information, such as your child’s name, your street and/or mailing address, gender, credit card, name, telephone number, and your child’s age ("User Information").

**Use and Sharing of Personally Identifiable Information.** Little Passports will not knowingly share PII with third parties except as set forth in our Privacy Policy and/or Terms of Use. We may share PII with third parties who provide Little Passports with administrative support services, such as, but not limited to, IT and related support services; authorization of credit card and check transactions; product warehousing, personalization, and order fulfillment; contest administration and fulfillment; and customer service activities. Such service providers may use cookies on our behalf in order to perform services for us. These service providers are granted access to some or all of your PII only as and to the extent necessary for them to perform their services for us. We may also share your name, address, phone number and purchase history with service providers that perform analytics to help us improve our products and Site, to market our services, and to identify new potential customers. These marketing service providers may share your name and contact information with their partners, but they will not identify you as a Little Passports customer. We may also share your PII with third parties with whom we offer co-branded or joint product and service promotions. If we provide PII to such service providers, all such PII will be so provided only under a confidentiality agreement at least as restrictive as the privacy provisions contained in this Privacy Policy.

We may release information, with or without notice to you, when necessary to collect amounts owed to us, comply with the law or a court order or an investigation. We also may release information to law enforcement to protect our rights, property, or other interests, including those of our users, when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss, or in connection with an investigation or prosecution of suspected or actual illegal activity, to prevent illegal activities or violations of our Terms of Use, or if we, in good faith, believe that disclosure is otherwise necessary or advisable.

If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, financing due diligence, reorganization, bankruptcy, receivership, sale of company assets, or transition of service to another provider, then your information may be sold or transferred as part of such a transaction as permitted by law and/or contract. In such event, we will endeavor to direct the transferee to use PII in a manner that is consistent with the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such PII was collected. In the event of a merger or acquisition, we may share information with future successors and/or assigns.

### Data Transfers

All PII collected via or by Little Passports may be stored anywhere in the world, including but not limited to the United States, in the cloud, on our servers, on the servers of our affiliates or the servers of our service providers. Your PII may be accessible to law enforcement or other authorities pursuant to a lawful request. By providing information to Little Passports, you consent to the storage of your PII in these locations.

**Notifications/Opt-out and Other Rights.** You have the right to opt out of certain uses and disclosures of your PII. Where you have consented to Little Passports’ processing of your PII, you may withdraw that consent at any time and opt-out to further processing by contacting us at the address below. Even if you opt-out, we may still collect and use non-personally identifiable information regarding your activities on our Site and/or information from the advertisements on third party websites for non-interest based advertising purposes, such as to determine the effectiveness of the advertisements.

It is Little Passports’ policy to provide notifications, whether such notifications are required by law or are for marketing or other business related purposes, to users via email notice, written or hard copy notice, or through conspicuous posting of such notice on the Site, as determined by Little Passports in its sole discretion. Little Passports reserves the right to determine the form and means of providing notifications to our users. By providing Little Passports with your email address you consent to our using such email address to send you notices in lieu of postal mail. We may also use your email address to send you other messages, including changes to Little Passports features and special offers. You may opt out of certain notifications by using the unsubscribe link found at the bottom of the email to opt-out of receiving future emails, changing your account settings, or by sending mail to the following postal address:

Little Passports, Inc.  
222 Sutter Street, Suite 750  
San Francisco, CA 94108  

We will process your request within a reasonable time after receipt. Opting out may prevent you from receiving email messages regarding updates, improvements, or special offers, and you may not opt out of certain types of notices, including but not limited to announcements regarding certain products, support of the Site or Services and other notices as may be required by law. If you or we have provided any third party with your information, you will have to contact such third-party directly with any opt-out request.

Do Not Track (“ **DNT** ”) is a privacy preference that users can set in certain web browsers. DNT is a way for users to inform websites and services that they do not want certain information about their webpage visits collected over time and across websites or online services. Please note that we do not respond to or honor DNT signals or similar mechanisms transmitted by web browsers.

As noted above, you may stop or restrict the placement of cookies on your computer or remove them from your browser by adjusting your web browser preferences. Please note that cookie-based opt-outs are not effective on mobile applications. However, on many mobile devices, application users may opt out of certain mobile ads via their device settings.

The online advertising industry also provides websites from which you may opt-out of receiving targeted ads from our data partners and our other advertising partners that participate in self-regulatory programs. You can access these, and also learn more about targeted advertising and consumer choice and privacy, at www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp, or <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/> and www.aboutads.info/choices/. You can also choose not to be included in Google Analytics [here](https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/google-analytics-opt-out/fllaojicojecljbmefodhfapmkghcbnh?hl=en)

To be clear, whether you are using our opt-out or an online industry opt-out, these cookie-based opt-outs must be performed on each device and browser that you wish to have opted-out. For example, if you have opted-out on your computer browser, that opt-out will not be effective on your mobile device. You must separately opt-out on each device. Advertisements on Third-Party websites that contain the AdChoices link and that link to this Privacy Policy may have been directed to you based on anonymous, non-personally identifiable information collected by advertising partners over time and across websites. These advertisements provide a mechanism to opt-out of the advertising partners’ use of this information for interest-based advertising purposes.

### Children’s Privacy

Little Passports takes the privacy of its child users seriously. As such, Little Passports will not request any information directly from a child except as described in the Subscription Purchased Before January 1, 2018 section below. A parent or guardian may provide information about their child when they are purchasing a Little Passports product, including the child’s name, age, gender, and mailing address.

To ensure that no PII is collected from child users, Little Passports has created the domain explore.littlepassports.com. Whenever a child is directed to visit a Little Passports webpage, they will be directed to a page on explore.littlepassports.com. Webpages on explore.littlepassports.com do not include any cookies or other tracking tools designed to create behavioral profiles or serve retargeted advertising to child users. As such, child users of Little Passports are not tracked or profiled for marketing or advertising purposes

### Subscriptions Purchased Before January 1, 2018

Little Passports stopped allowing the creation of user accounts on January 1, 2018. For subscriptions purchased before January 1, 2018, children may create accounts and log into the webpages on explore.littlepassports.com/board using credentials included in the kit they received in the mail. For users who registered for these accounts before January 1, 2018, Little Passports stores a first name, username, and password, and may store the user’s gender and birthday if he or she provided it. The username cannot be used to contact the user online.

We will maintain your child’s user account in accordance with this Privacy Policy, our Terms of Use, and any applicable laws at all times. Please read our Terms of Use for more information on the content and materials that Little Passports allows to be posted on our websites.

For accounts created before January 1, 2018, parents may review your child’s PII, request to have it deleted from our systems, and to limit further collection and use of your child’s PII. Before disclosing child-specific information, we may verify your identity through means such as the following: obtaining a signed form from you via postal mail or fax, receiving an email from you accompanied by your digital signature, or receiving an email from you combined with a unique identifier such as a password. If you suspect that your child has offered PII in error and/or you wish us to remove their information from our database, we are happy to do so. Please contact us at [customerservice@littlepassports.com](mailto:customerservice@littlepassports.com) or at the mailing address below and be sure to include the following:

your child's name and email address  
your name and email address  
the name of Little Passports

Little Passports, Inc.  
222 Sutter Street, Suite 750  
San Francisco, CA 94108

If our registration system is ever changed in a way that would collect PII from a child under the age of 13, we will send an email to such user’s parents or guardian requesting their consent to our collection of PII from their child. If the parent or guardian does not provide their consent, we will delete that child's information from our database. We will not collect any additional information from your child without your consent.

### Data Retention

We retain the PII we receive as described in this Privacy Policy for as long as you use our Services or as necessary to fulfill the purpose(s) for which it was collected, provide our Services, resolve disputes, establish legal defenses, conduct audits, pursue legitimate business purposes, enforce our agreements, and comply with applicable laws.

### Security

We have implemented technical and organizational measures designed to secure your PII from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration or disclosure. Be aware, however, that the Internet is not 100% secure, and we cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat those measures or use your PII for improper purposes. We cannot ensure the security of any information transmitted to us over the Internet, and we accept no liability for any unintentional disclosure of such information. You acknowledge that you provide your PII at your own risk. You also acknowledge that many portions of the Site are password protected. Do not share your passwords with anyone. You are solely responsible for any actions taken on the Site under your account.

By using the Site or providing PII to us, you agree that we may communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use of the Site or the Services. If we learn of a security system’s breach, we may attempt to notify you electronically by posting a notice on the Site or sending an e-mail to you. You may have a legal right to receive this notice in writing.

### Compromise of PII

In the event that PII is compromised as a result of a breach of security, we will promptly notify those persons whose PII has been compromised, in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law.

Please direct any questions that you may have regarding our Privacy Statement at any time to [customerservice@littlepassports.com](mailto:customerservice@littlepassports.com).

### International Users

By using the Site, you understand and agree that Little Passports will transfer data to the United States. By choosing to visit the Site, utilize the Services or otherwise provide information to us, you agree that any dispute over privacy or the terms contained in this Privacy Policy will be governed by the laws of California and the United States and the adjudication of any disputes arising in connection with Little Passports or the Site will be in accordance with the User Agreement.

If you are visiting from the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use, please note that you are agreeing to the transfer of your information to the United States and to processing of your data globally. By providing your PII, you consent to any transfer and processing in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy and/or data practices, please contact us at the following e-mail address, telephone number, or mailing address:

Little Passports, Inc.  
222 Sutter Street, Suite 750  
San Francisco, CA 94108  
(415) 496-6624

### Additional clauses for Australian customers (April 2017)

**Does PII leave Australia?**

We may disclose PII outside of Australia to third party service providers and other selected third parties described above, including those located in the United States.

**Access or correction of PII and questions about this Privacy Policy**

If you would like to access or correct the PII which we hold about you, or you have a question or complaint about our use of your PII please contact us on [customerservice@littlepassports.com](mailto:customerservice@littlepassports.com). When contacting us please provide as much detail as possible in relation to your question, comment or complaint.

We will take any privacy complaint seriously and any complaint will be assessed with the aim of resolving any issue in a timely and efficient manner. We request that you cooperate with us during this process and provide us with any relevant information that we may need. If you are not satisfied with the outcome of our assessment of your complaint, you may wish to contact the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner.
